Finding Aid for the Paul Jordan Smith Papers LSC.0267
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscript Material by Paul Jordan Smith
  - American Literature Since the World War. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf, typescript and holograph. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The American Novel. n.p., n.d.; 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - The American Novel Comes of Age. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - American Tradition in Literature. n.p., n.d.; 16 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - [Amiel, Henri-Frederic, 1821-1881]. [Los Angeles, (?)]., 1920s; 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Annie Laurie. n.p., n.d.; 9 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Isolationism. n.p, 193_.; 3 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Art and Religion n.p, 7 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - [Astor, John Jacob, 1864-1912]. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Ballyhooey in Heaven. Los Angeles. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - [Beresford, John Davys, 1873- ]. n.p., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Bernard Shaw and Frank Harris. n.p., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Bernard Shaw. The Protest of a Puritan. n.p., n.d.; 39 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Bible for Skeptics. n.p., 1920s(?).; 15 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 16)
    Published in On Strange Altars by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Albert and Charles Boni, 1924.
  - Birds and Book-Collectors. n.p., 4 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Book reviews. v.p, v.d.; 100 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - [Browne, Sir Thomas, 1605-1682]. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript Material Relating to Samuel Butler
    - The Centenary of Samuel Butler. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, typescript carbon. Incomplete. (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - [Notes]. n.p., n.d.; 17 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - [Untitled]. n.p., n.d.; 16 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - [Untitled]. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - [Untitled]. n.p., n.d.; 7 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - [Carpenter, Edward, 1844-1929]. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Casanova. n.p., Published in On Strange Altars by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Albert and Charles Boni, n.d. 1924.; 21 leaves. (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - [Censorship]. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - [Children's literature] Los Angeles, 1962.; 9 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 25, Folder 28)
    With this: Program for Second Annual Awards Banquet honoring Authors and Illustrators of Children's Literature Residing in Southern California. Los Angeles State College. Los Angeles, November 17, 1962. 1 item.
  - The Conscientious Objector. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - The City of Dreadful Night. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 25, Folder 30)
    Review of James Thomson's poem.
  - Curing Ham. Los Angeles, 1948.; 5 leaves, typescript. (Box 25, Folder 31)
    With this: Correspondence with Mavis McIntosh re publication of article in Gourmet magazine. 4 items (7 leaves).
  - [Debate notes]. n.p., n.d.; 16 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Desire as a Developmental Agency. n.p., 1907.; 10 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Development of the English Novel. n.p., n.d.; 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - [Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870]. n.p., 1968.; 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 35)
    Notes for a speech on Dickens.
  - Does America Need a Dictator? n.p, n.d.; 3 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 36)
    Debate notes.
  - A Dog's Life. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - [Dostoieffsky, sic]. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - [Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945]. n.p., n.d.; 10 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Education. n.p., n.d.; 25 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - [Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939]. Los Angeles(?), (?). Published in On Strange Altars by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Albert and Charles Boni, 1920s 1924.; 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - [Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882]. n.p., n.d.; 20 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Emerson's Theory of Poetry. n.p., n.d.; 9 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - English Country. n.p., n.d.; 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Erotica. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - Escape. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Ethical Imperatives for an Atomic Age. Los Angeles, 1946. (Box 26)
    Commencement address by Paul Jordan Smith given at the University of Chattanooga. Chattanooga, Tennessee, June 3, 1946.
    - [Notes and outline]., 11 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - [Fragments]., 6 leaves, typescript carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - [Draft]., 15 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - [Draft]., 16 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - [Text]., 13 leaves, typescript. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      With this printed copies of text. 3 items.
    - [Another copy]., 13 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - [Another copy]., 13 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      With this presentation text and citation text with carbon copy from the University of Chattanooga, signed David A. Lockmiller (2 leaves).
      Text of Robert Sparks Walker Audubon Society memorial to Paul Jordan Smith (1 leaf).
  - Examination for novel. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Examination questions for literature course.
  - The Faith and Frustration of a Literary Editor. n.p., 14 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Footnote Smith. [Los Angeles, 1957].; 10 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    With this notes, research material, correspondence. 18 items.
  - Footnote Smith. [Los Angeles, 1957].; 12 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    Published in American Book Collector, vol.7 no.8 (April 1957) pp.3-7.
  - [Flaubert, Gustave, 1821-1880]. n.p., n.d.; 16 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - The Four Oaks Mystery by Stephen Beloyser, pseudonym of Paul Jordan Smith(?). n.p., n.d.; 9 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - [France, Anatole, 1844-1924]. n.p., n.d.; 26 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - The Grapes of Wrath by John Steinbeck. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, typescript. (Box 26, Folder 15)
    Book review.
  - Great Literature. n.p., n.d.; 28 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Guilty Pleads. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript Material Relating to Thomas Hardy
    - [Lecture notes]. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - [Lecture notes]. n.p., n.d.; 19 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - [Lecture notes]. n.p., n.d.; 18 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - [Lecture notes]. n.p., n.d.; 15 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Henry George and a Free Society. Los Angeles, 1950.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 22)
    With this Ephemera and correspondence. 3 items (4 leaves).
  - History of American Civilization. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Holy Land. n.p., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - The Hope of the World. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Ideas for novel. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf, typescript and holograph. (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Ideas for novels [and other notes]. n.p., ca. 20 leaves, of 50 leaves, in black looseleaf binder. Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Is Progress Real? n.p, n.d.; 4 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Jacques Barzun and the Intellectuals. Los Angeles, 1960.; 11 leaves, Holograph, typescript and printed. (Box 26, Folder 29)
    Speech given to members of the Severance Club, June 10, 1960.
  - [James, Henry, 1843-1916]. Los Angeles(?), 1920s(?).; 6 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - James Joyce and William Faulkner. n.p., 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - John Bunyan's Pilgrim's Progress. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Kay Mulvey's Open House. [Los Angeles], 1952.; 6 leaves, typescript carbon and holograph. (Box 26, Folder 33)
    Notes for Paul Jordan Smith's appearance on television talk show.
  - Kit Carson in California. n.p., n.d.; 10 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Kit Carson in California. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - [Lawrence, David Herbert, 1885-1930]. n.p., n.d.; 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Light Through Labor. n.p., n.d.; 2 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Los Angeles. n.p., n.d.; 21 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Lucretius. n.p., n.d.; 15 leaves, Holograph. (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Major and Minor Fiction. n.p., 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - A Man of Parts. n.p., Summer 1925.; ca. 50 leaves, in bound notebook. Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    With ca. 15 leaves, of additional short story material.
  - Mark Twain. Los Angeles(?), 192_.; 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - [Masters, Edgar Lee, 1869-1950]. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - [Maugham, William Somerset, 1874-1966]. n.p., n.d.; 12 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Medley. n.p., [May 1925].; ca. 35 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    With this ephemera. 3 items.
  - [The Memoirs of Captain Peter Drake]. n.p., n.d.; 11 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - [Mencken, Henry Louis, 1880-1956]. Draft of letter to H. leaves, Mencken from Paul Jordan Smith. Claremont, California, 6 October 1924.; 10 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Modern Psychology in the Modern World. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Modern Tendencies in American Literature. n.p., 3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - [The Modern World and O'Neill]. n.p., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - [Montaigne, Michel Eyquem de, 1533-1592]. n.p., n.d.; 17 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - [Morality/Immorality]. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - [Morgan, Caradoc]. n.p., n.d.; ca. 20 leaves, in composition notebook. Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    With this: notes concerning Robert Burton, ca. 25 leaves, in composition notebook.
  - [Morgan, Caradoc]. n.p., n.d.; 19 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - The Mystery of Things. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - [Nathan, Robert, 1894- ]. n.p., n.d.; 2 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - [Nathan, Robert, 1894- ]. n.p., n.d.; 10 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - [Notes for essays]. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - [Notes for proposed anthology]. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Novels of the Old and New South. n.p., 2 leaves, Holograph. (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - One Clear Call. n.p., n.d.; ca. 20 leaves, Holograph. In bound notebook. (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - One Clear Call. n.p., n.d.; 22 leaves, typescript. (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - The Philosophy of Emerson. n.p., n.d.; 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - The Philosophy of Faust. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Pick and Choose. n.p., 1920s(?).; 27 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Pleasures and Pains of Book Collecting. [Los Angeles, 1956].; 15 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Speech given to UCLA Friends of the Library, 1956.
  - Pleasures and Perils of Book Collecting. [Los Angeles, 1956].; 22 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Pleasures and Perils of Book Collecting. [Los Angeles, 1956].; 22 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - [Poems]. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Poems by various authors.
  - [Powys, Llewelyn, 1884-1939]. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - [Progress]. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - [Progress]. n.p., n.d.; 12 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - [Quotations]. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - [Reach, Charles]. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - The Regional Novel. n.p., n.d.; 9 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Reviewer's Christmas Nightmare. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - A Reviewer's Qualifications. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf, typescript. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - The Rise of the Idyll. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Rules of the Game. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - [Sermon notes] n.p., 1910s(?).; 6 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - [Sermon notes] n.p., 1910s(?).; 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - [The Secret Garden] Los Angeles, 1949; 1 leaf, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 20)
    Paul Jordan Smith's introduction to a motion picture trailer for the screen adaptation of Frances Hodgson Burnett's novel.
    With this: Correspondence and outline of motion picture trailer from Frank Whitlock for screen adaptation of The Secret Garden by Frances Hodgson Burnett (6 leaves, and envelope).
    - [Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616]. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph and typescript. 1 clipping. (Box 28, Folder 20a)
  - [Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968]. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Der Skunk. n.p., 1939.; 13 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Some Indirections for Selecting Good Books. n.p., 12 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 23)
    Speech given at Whittier, California.
  - [Some Indirections for Selecting Good Books]. n.p., 15 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Something of a Record. n.p., n.d.; 7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - --Another copy. n.p., n.d.; 7 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Standards. n.p., 5 leaves, typescript. (Box 28, Folder 27)
    With this clipping. 1 item.
  - [Steffins debate]. n.p., n.d.; 10 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - [Sterne, Laurence, 1713-1768]. n.p., n.d.; 16 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - [Strindberg, August, 1849-1912]. n.p., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - [Swift and Aldous Huxley]. n.p., 10 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Theory of Poetry. n.p., n.d.; ca. 80 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 32)
    Lecture notes, Prof. Kurtz.
  - [Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862]. n.p., n.d.; 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Tired Radicals. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - The Tonic of Vision. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Twentieth Century Debts. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Two Lively English Bachelors. [Los Angeles], February 17, 1596.; 25 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - [Types of fiction]. n.p., n.d.; 14 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - [Types of novels]. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Manuscript material relating to Ulysses by James Joyce. (Box 28)
    - Ulysses. [Notes] n.p., 1924(?).; 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 28, Folder 40)
      With this: Saturday Review of Literature, vol.10 no.30 (February 10, 1934). Smith's note on front cover refers to Random House advertisement, pp.474-475.
    - Ulysses... a Study of Inwit. n.p., 1924.; 19 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Ulysses. Translation of article in La Nouvelle Revue Francais by Valery Larbaud. (?)., 1930s; 14 leaves, typescript. (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Ulysses. [Outline] n.p., 1920s(?).; 29 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 43)
      Includes outline of the Odyssey. Published in A Key to the Ulysses of James Joyce by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Covici-Friede, 1927.
    - A Key to the Ulysses of James Joyce by Paul Jordan Smith. n.p., 1927.; 8 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 28, Folder 44)
      Includes dedication, preface and introduction.
    - A Key to the Ulysses of James Joyce by Paul Jordan Smith. n.p., 1927.; 81 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 28, Folder 45)
      With this ephemera. 1 piece.
      Published in New York, Covici-Friede, 1927.
  - [Untitled]. n.p., n.d.; 6 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - [Untitled]. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - [Untitled]. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - [Untitled play]. n.p., n.d.; 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - [Untitled play]. n.p., n.d.; 60 leaves, typescript carbon and holograph. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Upton Sinclair. n.p., n.d.; 3 leaves, typescript. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    SEE ALSO box 28.
  - Vincent Starrett, a Creative Bibliophile. n.p., n.d.; 9 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Woolf and Elinor Wylie. n.p., 10 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    With this clipping of The Pebble. 1 item.
  - Voltaire. n.p., n.d.; 8 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - [Ward, Lester F.]. n.p., n.d.; 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - [Wells, Herbert George, 1866-1946]. n.p., n.d.; 19 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - [Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892]. n.p., 192_.; 19 leaves, Holograph. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - [William Blake and Arthur Machen]. n.p., 8 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - [Wolfe, Thomas, 1900-1938]. n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Words and Masters of Words. n.p., 13 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Material Relating to World War II
    - Clipping, June 28, 1940.; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence. n.p., 1940.; 3 items (3 leaves). (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Press release. Evanston, Illinois, August 22, 1941.; 1 item (3 leaves). (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Manuscript Material (Box 29)
      - Fifth Columnists in America. n.p., 1941(?).; 4 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Fifth Columnists in America. n.p., 1941(?).; 3 leaves, typescript. (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - List of fifth columnists. n.p.,., 1941; 2 leaves, typescript. (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - Made in Germany. n.p., 1941(?).; 7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - Made in Germany. n.p., 1941(?).; 8 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - No Gulls for Moguls. An American Reader's Guide Through the Mazes of World Propaganda by Paul Jordan Smith. Revised and enlarged from two articles which appeared in the Times Sunday Magazine, June 30 and August 25, 1940. (Box 29, Folder 23)
        - --7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29, Folder 24)
        - --9 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29, Folder 25)
        - --22 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 29, Folder 26)
        - --3 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon. (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - [Untitled article] Los Angeles, 1940-1941(?).; 5 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 29, Folder 28)
        With this: Stalin's American Power by Max Eastman, The American Mercury, December 1941 (5 leaves).
  - Fragments, incomplete manuscript material. n.p., n.d.; ca. 100 leaves. (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Fragments, incomplete manuscript material. n.p., n.d.; ca. 75 leaves. (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Fragments, incomplete manuscript material. n.p., n.d.; ca. 75 leaves. (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Lectures given by Paul Jordan Smith, 1914-1916. (Box 30)
    Mr. Smith was an instructor of English at the University of California at Berkeley during this period.
    - Announcements, University of California at Berkeley extension mailing envelopes., 9 items. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - American Drama., 15 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - [Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850]., 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - [Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931]., 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - [Browning, Robert, 1812-1889]., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - [Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958]. San Francisco, June 31, 1920.; 2 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - [Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924]., 3 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Dickens and Thackeray., 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Fiction of Power and Purpose., 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 9)
      Introduction to course. This lecture deals primarily with Stendahl's The Red and the Black.
    - [Gourmont, Rémy de, 1858-1915]., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - [Ibsen, Henrik, 1828-1906]., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Jean Christophe., 21 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - [Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826]., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - [Key, Ellen Karolina Sofia, 1849-1926]., 17 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Message of Drama., 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - The Message of the Radical Woman., 19 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Modern Literature and American Social Problems., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - The Newer Spiritual Values. Los Gatos, 1914-1916.; 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Nietzsche and the War., 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - [Pater, Walter Horatio, 1839-1894]., 8 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Scott and Jane Austen., 22 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - The Spirit of Belgium., 16 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 22)
      With this clippings. 3 items.
    - The Spirit of England., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - The Spirit of France., 16 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - The Spirit of Germany., 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - The Spirit of Italy., 19 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - The Spirit of Russia., 11 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - [Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900]., 18 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - [United]., 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - [United]., 5 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - [United]., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - [Notes]., 3 leaves, Holograph. (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Trends in Seventeenth Century Prose. Los Angeles, 1950-1951. (Box 31)
    English 263 A, UCLA extension course taught by Paul Jordan Smith.
    - Enrollment cards, parking information, memoranda., 7 items. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Class work assignments., 5 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Lecture notes., 9 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Lecture notes., 9 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Lecture notes., 15 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Reading list., 22 items. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Student paper. The Treatment of Religion in the Utopian Literature of the Sixteenth and Seventeenth Centuries by J. Monteverde., 20 leaves, typescript. (Box 31, Folder 7)